archiesonline.com 2002-04-08

# Archiesonline.com | The Perfect Place to Meet, Greet and Gift

Protecting privacy is not a new endeavor for ARCHIESONLINE.COM. ARCHIESONLINE.COM has a long-standing tradition of recognizing and protecting the privacy of customers who use its telecommunication networks. The company maintains strict customer information privacy policies and uses state of the art technologies to safeguard customer information and communications from unauthorized intrusions. ARCHIESONLINE.COM recognizing the growth of online services, including Internet services, has created additional privacy concerns, particularly for consumers. Online privacy concerns focus on the protection of "customer identifiable" information, which an individual or other customer reasonably expects to be kept private. As the term suggests, "customer identifiable" information is information which can be associated with a specific individual or entity, including, for example, a customer's name, address, or telephone number, e-mail address, and information about online activities that are directly linked to them. It is common practice and often a necessity for companies, governments, or other organizations to collect customer identifiable information in order to conduct business and offer services. For example, a telecommunications provider may collect customer identifiable information, such as name, address, telephone number, and a variety of other information in the course of billing and providing telephone service to a customer. Some activities on the Internet follow very familiar patterns. Consumers signing up for an Internet access service, for example, are usually asked to provide name, address, telephone number and credit card and other information that is typical when the consumer orders a product or service. Similarly, business web sites may ask visitors to supply information about themselves, particularly when information, services or merchandise are requested, but often simply to be able to better target the company's services to the customer's interests and requirements. 

ARCHIESONLINE.COM is committed to safeguard your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you make full use of our many offerings. This policy may change from time to time so please check back periodically. Read about how ARCHIESONLINE.COM treats the privacy of all its customers and in particular about vulnerable children.

  * **What personally identifiable information does ARCHIESONLINE.COM collect from me?**  
ARCHIESONLINE.COM collects information in several ways from different parts of our network of web sites. Information is gathered when you register. During registration ARCHIESONLINE.COM asks for your name, e-mail address, birth date, gender, zip code, occupation, industry and personal interests and other specified information. This is sought from you voluntarily, as ARCHIESONLINE.COM would be better able to customize your experience. Thus the more precise and accurate the information provided, the better the service that you get from ARCHIESONLINE.COM. On registration, ARCHIESONLINE.COM gives you an ID and you are then able to take the best advantage of all of Archie's many offerings. However, in addition to registration, ARCHIESONLINE.COM would also ask you for personal information at other times, including, (but not limited to), when you enter a sweepstakes, contest or promotion sponsored by ARCHIESONLINE.COM and/or our many partners; when you make a purchase using ARCHIESONLINE.COM Shopping; when you post a ARCHIESONLINE.COM Classified ad; when you submit a listing for a web site; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact ARCHIESONLINE.COM we may keep a record of that correspondence. ARCHIESONLINE.COM also occasionally asks users to complete surveys that we use for research purposes. Wherever ARCHIESONLINE.COM collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.  

  * **What are cookies and how does ARCHIESONLINE.COM use them?  
**A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer's hard drive. To give you optimally customized and personalized services ARCHIESONLINE.COM uses Cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. All sites on ARCHIESONLINE.COM where you are prompted to log-in or that are customizable require that you accept cookies. Generally, we use cookies to:

>   1. Remind us of whom you are and to access your account information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. This cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services. ARCHIESONLINE.COM also uses cookies to store your zip code for other services.
> 
>   2. Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing ARCHIESONLINE.COM is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior. 
> 
>   3. Assist merchants in ARCHIESONLINE.COM Stores to track visits to and business at their stores, and to process the items in your shopping basket. This information collected by cookies is sometimes called "click stream" or "click trail" and may also describe which pages you have seen in each merchant's store. 
> 
>   4. Track your progress and number of entries in some of our promotions, sweepstakes and contests. When an ARCHIESONLINE.COM-hosted promotion uses cookies, the information written to the cookie indicates the player's progress through the promotion, and may be used to track entries, submissions, and status in prize drawings.
> 
>   5. Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of Archie's network of web sites you have visited and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on ARCHIESONLINE.COM a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.
> 
> 

> 
> However, you should know that advertising networks that serve ads onto ARCHIESONLINE.COM might also use their own cookies. Thus ARCHIESONLINE.COM also collects IP addresses for system administration and to report aggregate information to our advertisers. In addition, ARCHIESONLINE.COM Mail includes IP addresses in outgoing mail message headers.

  * **How does ARCHIESONLINE.COM use my information?**  
ARCHIESONLINE.COM’ primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, with a customized and personalized experience on our network of sites, which includes interactive communications, online shopping and many other types of services, most of which are completely free to you. In order to provide services free of charge, we display advertisements. By knowing a little about you, ARCHIESONLINE.COM is able to deliver more relevant advertisements and content, and hence better service, to you. In our role of delivering targeted advertisements, ARCHIESONLINE.COM plays the middleman. Advertisers give us an advertisement and tell us the type of audience they want to reach, (for example, males over 35 years old). ARCHIESONLINE.COM takes the advertisement and displays it to users meeting those criteria. In this process, the advertiser never has access to individual account information. Only ARCHIESONLINE.COM has access to individual’s accounts. This kind of advertisement targeting is done with banner ads as well as promotional e-mail through which ARCHIESONLINE.COM delivers. Only special offers would be sent by via e-mail from ARCHIESONLINE.COM and only if you have indicated in your account preferences that you would like to receive them. You can always change your account preferences at any time. ARCHIESONLINE.COM does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, during a promotion, from our server log files or from surveys. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis. ARCHIESONLINE.COM may share this aggregated data with advertisers or business partners.  

  * **Who is collecting information?**  
When you are on an ARCHIESONLINE.COM site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with ARCHIESONLINE.COM alone, unless it is specifically stated otherwise. However, where services are offered in conjunction with other partner merchants, for providing co-branded service to you, it would be necessary for us to share your personal information with our partner merchant. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any company other than ARCHIESONLINE.COM, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. Promotions that run on ARCHIESONLINE.COM may be sponsored by companies other than ARCHIESONLINE.COM or may be co-sponsored by ARCHIESONLINE.COM and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion may be shared with the sponsor. If data is shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion if you don't want your data to be shared. Currently, most ARCHIESONLINE.COM promotions are limited to Indian residents. Please be aware that ARCHIESONLINE.COM Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites that have links on our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. This privacy statement does not cover the information, secrecy, privacy and other trading practices of those Internet access partners, advertisers, and web sites linked to ARCHIESONLINE.COM.  

  * **With whom does ARCHIESONLINE.COM share my information?  
**As a general rule, ARCHIESONLINE.COM will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as when we believe in good faith that the law requires it or under the circumstances. Please see the Terms of Service or Use Agreements for each of our products and services for more detailed information about how your personal information may be shared. The following are some illustrations of some of the ways that your information may be disclosed, viz.: -

ARCHIESONLINE.COM may disclose your personal information to business partners or sponsors, but this is specifically described to you prior to data collection or prior to transferring the data. Details of shared use can be found in specific Terms of Service or Use Agreements, and sweepstakes and promotions rules. Some or all data collected during ARCHIESONLINE.COM promotion may be shared with a sponsor. If personally identifying data about you is shared, we will tell you before we collect or transfer the data. Many promotions offer opportunities to request additional information from sponsors. By requesting more information, you give ARCHIESONLINE.COM permission to transfer your personal information to the sponsor so they can fulfill your request. In many instances, only your e-mail address will be shared. If more information is shared with the sponsor, you will be notified prior to the transfer.   
If you make a purchase from a store hosted by ARCHIESONLINE.COM or a partner merchant of ARCHIESONLINE.COM, the information obtained during your visit to those stores, and the information you give such as your credit card number and contact information, is provided to the merchants. This is to enable transactions to take place. For this you specifically give your consent and approval and the use of this site or the relevant links or access thereto without any further act, deed or thing constituting such incontrovertible consent.  
Partner Merchants or others listed in ARCHIESONLINE.COM site or in ARCHIESONLINE.COM Stores have separate privacy and data collection practices. ARCHIESONLINE.COM has no responsibility or liability for these independent policies. For more information regarding them, their store, and their privacy policies, return to that store's home page and click on their respective information links(s).  
On the ARCHIESONLINE.COM Auctions site, we currently provide the information necessary to facilitate the auction transaction between the buyer and the seller.   
From time to time, you may be offered the opportunity to receive materials or special offers from third parties. If you opt-in to receive information from these third parties, ARCHIESONLINE.COM will, (with your permission), share your name and e-mail address with them.  
Under confidentiality agreements, ARCHIESONLINE.COM may match user information with third party data. Also, ARCHIESONLINE.COM discloses aggregated user statistics, (for example, 45% of our users are females), in order to describe our services to current and prospective partners, advertisers, and other third parties, and for other lawful purposes.  
ARCHIESONLINE.COM may also disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating ARCHIESONLINE.COM’ Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with, (either intentionally or unintentionally), ARCHIESONLINE.COM’ rights or property, other ARCHIESONLINE.COM users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. ARCHIESONLINE.COM may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.  

  * **What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?**  
ARCHIESONLINE.COM may, from time to time, send you e-mail regarding our products and services. In addition, if you indicated upon registration that you are interested in receiving offers or information from ARCHIESONLINE.COM and our Merchant Partners, we may occasionally send you direct mail about products and services that we feel may be of interest to you. Only ARCHIESONLINE.COM, (or agents working on behalf of ARCHIESONLINE.COM and under confidentiality agreements), will send you these direct mailings and only if you indicated that you do not object to these offers. If you do not want to receive such mailings, simply tell us when you give us your personal information. Or, at any time you can easily edit your account information to receiving such offers and discontinue mailings. You will need your ARCHIESONLINE.COM ID and Password in order to access the same.  
On some types of ARCHIESONLINE.COM promotions, we will ask for your e-mail address in order to update you on your score, entries, and status in prize drawings. When you participate in these types of promotions, you automatically receive promotion-related e-mail, unless you choose the no-email option that some promotions offer. Occasionally these promotion-related e-mail messages might include targeted advertisements.  
You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. If you choose to reject all cookies you will be unable to use those ARCHIESONLINE.COM services that require registration in order to participate. These services include, (but are not limited to) ARCHIESONLINE.COM Mail, My ARCHIESONLINE.COM Page, Calendar, Chat, Message Boards, and Ready Recall. You can still use ARCHIESONLINE.COM Shopping and ARCHIESONLINE.COM Auctions and many other ARCHIESONLINE.COM sites even if you do not accept cookies. ARCHIESONLINE.COM does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.  

  * **What is ARCHIESONLINE.COM’ policy on allowing me to update, correct, or delete my personally identifiable information?  
**You may edit your account information and your profile at any time by using your ARCHIESONLINE.COM ID and password. If you have forgotten your password, please click on “forgot password” to request a new password. For all other problems signing in to ARCHIESONLINE.COM, please click on csc@archiesonline.com and complete this form. Your Archies account can be deleted or deactivated, but doing so will result in not being able to access any “members-only” area of the Archies network. If you have saved the confirmation e-mail you received when you first created your Archies account, you can use the URL provided in that message to delete your account at any time. Please contact csc@archiesonline.com for further instructions about deleting or deactivating your ARCHIESONLINE.COM account. Residual information will remain within our archive records. If you are participating in an ARCHIESONLINE.COM promotion and you wish to update your e-mail address on the promotion mailing list or to quit a promotion and cease receiving promotion-related e-mail, please contact [csc@archiesonline.com](mailto:csc@archiesonline.com).  

  * **How does ARCHIESONLINE.COM protect my personal, financial and health-related information?**  
Keeping your personal, financial and health-related information privacy is vitally important to us. As with all information, ARCHIESONLINE.COM will never rent or sell your personal, financial or health-related information. This includes information kept in your ARCHIESONLINE.COM Portfolio. If you use ARCHIESONLINE.COM Online Banking Access, ARCHIESONLINE.COM will work with your financial institution to present your account balances and history to you on your customized ARCHIESONLINE.COM pages. In order to present your financial information to you, ARCHIESONLINE.COM receives that information from your financial institution in an encrypted format and presents it to you over a secure-server. ARCHIESONLINE.COM Online Banking Access is regularly updated. ARCHIESONLINE.COM encrypts this data and stores it on our secure servers. Knowing your use of certain services or features might help us to offer you better and more relevant content and advertisements. But as with all personally identifiable information, we do not make this available to any third parties without your permission. Any user statistics that we may provide to prospective advertisers or partners regarding financial product or service usage on ARCHIESONLINE.COM are provided in the aggregate only and do not include any personally identifiable information about any individual user. Please note that there are several places on the ARCHIESONLINE.COM network of Web sites where you can transmit credit card information in order to complete a purchase transaction or for verification purposes. Any time we ask for a credit card number we transmit that credit card number in an encrypted format. We use industry-standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption.  

  * **What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?**  
Your ARCHIESONLINE.COM Account Information and ARCHIESONLINE.COM Profile are password-protected so that you and only you have access to this personal information. You may edit your account information and profile by using your ARCHIESONLINE.COM ID and password. We recommend that you do not divulge your password to anyone. ARCHIESONLINE.COM will never ask you for your password in an unsolicited phone call or in an unsolicited e-mail. Also remember to sign out of your ARCHIESONLINE.COM account and close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet cafe. ARCHIESONLINE.COM has users all over the world. When you give ARCHIESONLINE.COM your personal information, that information may be sent electronically to servers outside of the country where you originally entered the information. In addition, that information may be used, stored and processed outside of the country where you entered that information. Whenever ARCHIESONLINE.COM handles personal information as described above, regardless of where this occurs, ARCHIESONLINE.COM takes steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service and this Privacy Policy. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet or any wireless network can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, ARCHIESONLINE.COM cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.  

  * **What about children's privacy?**  
Naturally, the safety of children is very important to us at ARCHIESONLINE.COM. ARCHIESONLINE.COM has ensured that its sites are children friendly and that these sites are fun and age-appropriate for our younger audience. ARCHIESONLINE.COM is a general audience web site that complies with all relevant laws applicable to children. When a child under age 13 attempts to register with ARCHIESONLINE.COM, we ask that they give the name and other particulars of their parent or guardian to establish the ARCHIESONLINE.COM account. ARCHIESONLINE.COM does not share personally identifying information about users who are under the age of 12 with business partners or other third parties. ARCHIESONLINE.COM will not contact users who are under the age of 12 about special offers or for marketing purposes. All ARCHIESONLINE.COM account holders, including parents and children with ARCHIESONLINE.COM Family Accounts, are subject to this Privacy Policy.  

  * **What else should I know about my privacy?  
**Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through e-mail, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online. 

**Additional Information**  
If you have a question that was not addressed in this privacy policy you may contact us at 

[csc@archiesonline.com](mailto:csc@archiesonline.com) or at the following address: 

**Archies Online.com Ltd  
** A-21/8, Phase - II, Naraina Industrial Area,  
New Delhi - 110028.  
Ph. No. 91-11-5893135/36.  
Fax No. 91-11-5893138
